Finding Aid for Louis A. Weil papers, 1904-1952
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Louis A. Weil papers
1904-1952
Weil, Louis A., 1878-1959.
85624 Aa 2; AC; UAx
Editor and publisher of the Port Huron Times Herald. Scrapbooks, correspondence, and photographs concerning his newspaper career and other Port Huron, Michigan, activities.
1 linear feet
2 oversize volumes
3 phonograph records
2.14 GB
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of F. Granger Weil (donor no. 5737 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Louis A. Weil was editor and publisher of the Port Huron Times Herald.
The collection is composed of four series: Correspondence; Miscellaneous; Scrapbooks; and Audio-Visual materials. One of the scrapbooks contains letters received from William Lyon Phelps, H. L. Mencken, Edgar A. Guest, Chase S. Osborn, Frank Murphy, Theodore Roosevelt and Arthur H. Vandenberg.
Subjects:
Journalists--Michigan--Port Huron.; American newspapers--Michigan--Port Huron.; Port Huron (Mich.); Port Huron times herald.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Celebrations.; Children.; Dwellings.; Families.; Horses.; Ice skating.; Interiors.; Journalists--Michigan--Port Huron.; Newspapers--Michigan--Port Huron.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Port Huron (Mich.); Port Huron (Mich.)--Restaurants.; Restaurants--Michigan--Port Huron.; Rodeos.; Weil, Louis A., 1878-1959.; Weil family.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
American newspapers--Michigan.; Weil, Louis A., 1878-1959.
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Black, Eugene F., 1903-1990
Contributors: Manuscripts
Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Genre Terms:
Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Tintypes.
- Correspondence, undated; 1904-1950; 1962
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1904-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1944, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1945, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950, 1962 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Papers concerning negotiations with the newspaper unions, 1947-1952; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning Holliday Motel (Canada) libel suit, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook concerning United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1913-1946 (Box 1)
    (include letters from William Lyon Phelps, H.L. Mencken, Edgar A. Guest, Chase Osborn, Frank Murphy, Arthur H. Vandenberg)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1913-1952; 2 volumes (Volume 1)
- Audio-visual
  - Photographs
    (see also tintypes stored separately with UAx images)
    - Early (Box 1)
    - Family Group (Box 1)
    - Family miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Friends, colleagues (Box 1)
    - Groups (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Audio-tapes (Box 1)
    [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
    - Composing Room Talk, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85624-SR-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Weil discusses history and issues of running the Port Huron Times Herald.)
    - Composing Room Talk, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85624-SR-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Weil discusses history and issues of running the Port Huron Times Herald.)
  - Phonograph records of broadcast featuring Supreme Court Justice Eugene Black in which he exposes "Michigan Gang", May 27, 1948; 3 phonograph records; 78 rpm
    - Phonograph records of broadcast featuring Supreme Court Justice Eugene Black in which he exposes "Michigan Gang", May 27, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Phonograph records of broadcast featuring Supreme Court Justice Eugene Black in which he exposes "Michigan Gang", May 27, 1948 (Box 2)
      (continued)
    - Phonograph records of broadcast featuring Supreme Court Justice Eugene Black in which he exposes "Michigan Gang", May 27, 1948 (Box 3)